http://www.libertytax.com/online/privacy-statement/#nevada-603a-policy

4104
Privacy Statement
Click here for updates to the Privacy Notice for Nevada's Chapter 603A and SB220 Click here for updates to the Privacy Notice for California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018
Online tax preparation has never been safer or more secure.
At JTH Tax, Inc., doing business as Liberty Tax Service® (“Liberty,” “we,” or “our”), we recognize the importance of protecting your personal information. We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of your information and want you to know the protective measures we take.
This Website Privacy Policy concerns the information we collect when you view our websites and our affiliated companies’ websites, including, www.esmarttax.com, www.esmarttax.com/ffa, www.freetax.com, www.libertytax.com, www.taxbrain.com, and www.libertytax.com/online, (collectively, our “Websites”). It also describes your choices regarding use, access and correction of your personal information. If you come to one of our offices for tax preparation you will be subject to a separate privacy policy disclosed to you when you use those services.
Liberty may also offer the ability to apply for financial products through various affiliated and non-affiliated companies. Our privacy policies, and those of our non-affiliated partners, may vary depending on the type of service or products offered. This privacy policy applies solely to our Websites.
If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third-party resolution provider (free of charge) here.
Tracking Technologies
If you use our Websites, we collect the following types of information:
We and our partners use cookies or similar technologies. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.
We use cookies for online customer support, and analytics service providers. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited.
Behavioral Targeting/Re-Targeting
We partner with a third-party ad network to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our ad network partner uses cookies and Web beacons to collect non-personal information about your activities on this and other Web sites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking here. Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.
We use Google AdSense to publish ads on this site. When you view or click on an ad a cookie will be set to help better provide advertisements that may be of interest to you on this and other Web sites. You may opt-out of the use of this cookie by visiting Google’s Advertising and Privacy page: http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html.
Log files. As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We do not link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you.
HTML5. We use Local Storage such as HTML5 to store content information and preferences. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity use LSOs such as HTML 5 to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs.
Personal Information We Collect.  If you choose to submit your contact information to indicate an interest in either a franchise or tax course, we receive from you your name, address, telephone number and e-mail address. If you choose to submit your e-mail address to indicate an interest in our electronic newsletter, we receive from you your e-mail address. We may receive your personal information, including (which includes, without limitation, your name, address, email or phone number) if you participate in any of our surveys or contests or if you request a service from us. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information.
Our website does not currently support “do not track” settings on your browser or have any similar mechanism that allows you to opt out of or otherwise control the collection of certain information about your online activities.
Tax Filing Information. If you choose to file your taxes with Liberty, we collect your SSN and DOB, as required, to complete your tax return.
If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our website, we will ask you for your friend’s name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the website. JTH Tax, Inc. stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the performance of our referral program.
Your friend may contact us at promotions@libtax.com to request that we remove this information from our database.
Geolocation by 3rd Party Vendors
Cellular geolocation services in calls made to Liberty Tax® toll free numbers are provided by AdGeo, Inc. Information about this service, the vendors terms of use and the vendor’s data retention policies may be found at http://www.adgeo.com/MobileTermsOfService.aspx. Information about the vendor’s privacy policy for this service may be found at http://www.adgeo.com/PrivacyPolicy.aspx. Your use of and explicit or implicit consent during the toll free calls indicates your acceptance of the vendor’s terms of use and privacy policies.
How We May Use the Information
We may use your information collected in the Websites to provide the services or products you requested, to process transactions that you initiate, to improve our services and Websites, for marketing or promotional purposes and to contact you regarding our services or your use of the Websites.
Information We Disclose
We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy. We do not sell your personal information to third parties.
Affiliated and non-affiliated third parties may be given access to your information only as permitted by law or upon your express authorization to process the transactions in which you have engaged us to perform. Our affiliated and non-affiliated third parties may offer you the opportunity to receive information concerning their products and services. If you elect to receive such communications from these third-parties, we may share your name and contact information.
If you have inputted information into our website to express an interest in being contacted about tax courses, your information is transferred to a local Liberty Tax Service® office, most of which are franchised, so the office may contact you. Also, we may contact you directly about a tax course in one of our offices, or an online tax course, or we may contact you about franchise opportunities with us.
If you entered your contact information into our website to express an interest in being contacted about a franchise opportunity, we use your information to contact you about this opportunity.
If you submitted your e-mail address to sign up for our electronic newsletter, we use your e-mail address to e-mail our newsletter to you and we may contact you about franchise opportunities with us. Out of respect for your privacy, you may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails, accessing the email preferences in your account settings page or you can contact us at privacy@libtax.com.
If you submitted your e-mail address to us for any purpose, we may contact you to invite you to prepare your tax return with us and send you marketing messages.
We may disclose or use the registration information that you provide when creating an account to show you tailored advertising or to send you marketing messages. We may disclose your registration information to non-affiliated third parties that perform operational, marketing, financial or accounting services for us. These companies are authorized to use your registration information only as necessary to provide these services to us. Such sharing will be done in accordance with applicable law.
If you submit your personal tax return information for the purposes of preparing and filing your tax returns, our use or disclosure of that information may be limited by the Internal Revenue Code, § 7216, the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act, and other law. We will not use or disclose to third parties your personal tax return information for any other purpose other than the preparing, assisting you in preparing, or filing your tax return, unless you authorize us by providing to us written consent to use or disclose or unless expressly required or authorized by law or pursuant to a court order.
We may disclose your information to non-affiliated third parties that perform operational, marketing or accounting services for us and who are required to use such information only to perform services on our behalf. Our sharing of information may be with a financial product provider with whom we have a joint-marketing agreement or non-financial companies that provides technical services such as software services. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us. Such sharing will be done in accordance with applicable law. We also may share aggregated, or de-identified information, which cannot reasonably be used to identify you.
In certain situations, JTH Tax, Inc. may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.
We may also disclose or transfer your information in response to legal process such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process or when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request, where required by applicable law, or if we are acquired by or merged with another company. If we are involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of our assets, you will be notified a prominent notice on our Website(s) of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.
Updating Your Information
Upon request, we will provide you with information about whether we hold, or process on behalf of a third party, any of your personal information. You may access, correct, or request deletion of your personal information by [logging into your account/ contacting us at (company email)/ by completing this form]. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe.
If you are using our Websites to prepare and file your tax returns, you may update your log in and password information by logging into your account or by contacting customer support at support@efile.libertytax.com. Other information we collect as described in this privacy policy is not stored in an online accessible format or does not identify you personally. For all other inquiries related to your information, including updating or deactivation, deleting or no longer using your submitted information please contact us via privacy@libtax.com or by postal mail to JTH Tax, Inc. c/o Privacy, 1716 Corporate Landing Parkway, Virginia Beach, Virginia 23454. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe.
We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services or as required under applicable law. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.
Do Not Call (DNC) Policy
At Liberty, we recognize the importance of protecting your personal information. We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of your information and want you to know the protective measures we take.
Liberty will adhere to all applicable and enforceable federal and state laws and regulations governing outbound telephone calls for the protection of the privacy of telephone consumers. The National Do Not Call Registry is managed by the Federal Trade Commission (FTC), the nation’s consumer protection agency. Liberty will not call any number appearing on the federal or state do not call list (unless permitted by applicable law) or the number of a person, who request not to receive telemarketing campaign calls made on the behalf of Liberty Tax Service®.
If you request not to receive calls from us, you will be placed on our internally maintained DNC list and will not be called for any future telemarketing campaigns. Upon your request, Liberty will document immediately. Please allow up to 30 days for your telephone number to be removed from any campaigns that are currently underway. You will remain on Liberty’s “Do Not Call “list for 5 years, unless you ask to be removed. Also, some states have Do Not Call laws that require Liberty to honor such request for a longer period of time, and it is Liberty’s policy to comply with those laws when applicable. When submitting a request via phone to be placed on the DNC list, all calls may be monitored or recorded. Liberty reserves the right to revise this “Do Not Call Policy”.
All employees that engage in outbound telephone solicitation are trained in this policy and are made aware of these procedures before they are allowed to place campaigns calls to consumers. Management reviews the policy with employees on a seasonal basis. If a consumer requests a copy of our “Do Not Call” Policy, Liberty will send a copy via U.S. mail or electronic mail. The “Do Not Call” policy is also posted on the Liberty intranet site under Owned and Operated Customer Care Center – DNC Policy.
Information Security
We maintain physical, electronic and procedural security measures that comply with applicable legal and regulatory standards to safeguard your personal information. Access to such information is restricted to those employees who are trained in the proper handling of client information and have a legitimate business need to access that information. We follow generally accepted standards, such as encryption and secure socket layer technology, to protect the personal information you submit to us, whether that information is in transit or at rest. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can contact us at privacy@libtax.com.
Additional Information
Links to 3rd Party Sites. Our Website(s) includes links to other Web sites whose privacy practices may differ from ours. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any Web site you visit.
Blogs. Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why. Our blog is also managed by a third-party application that may require you to register to post a comment. We do not have access or control of the information posted to the blog. You will need to contact or login into the third-party application if you want the personal information that was posted to the comments section removed. To learn how the third-party application uses your information, please review their privacy policy.
Social Media Widgets
Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.
Acceptance of These Terms
You understand that any information you provide to us through any of the Websites shall be governed by this privacy policy. If you do not agree with these terms, you should not use the Websites. Your continued use of the Websites indicates your acceptance of these terms.
This privacy policy is effective November 10, 2017.
Because privacy is important, we pledge to work with you to protect and safeguard the security of your personal customer information. If this privacy policy changes, we will notify you of the changes by posting a notice on our Websites. If we make any material changes we will notify you by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.
If you have any questions about this privacy policy, you may contact us by e-mail at privacy@libtax.com or by mail at Privacy, Liberty Tax Service®, 1716 Corporate Landing Parkway, Virginia Beach, Virginia 23454.
Nevada Security and Privacy of Personal Information Statute - Chapter 603A
In accordance with the Nevada Security and Privacy of Personal Information Statute - Chapter 603A; Liberty Tax Service® generally collects the following personal information from its customers:
Name
Address
Social Security Number
Email Address
Telephone Number
Dependent's Name
Dependent's Address
Dependent's Email Address
The above information may be shared with financial institutions, if a refund transfer, consumer credit product, reloadable prepaid debit card or advance have been requested; a company which offers identity theft protection, if such protection has been requested; or third-party email and text platforms for communication and marketing purposes.
Any changes to the above information will be reflected on this website.
Liberty Tax Service® does not allow third-parties to collect the above information which has been gathered from our customers through their on-line activities.
Individuals may contact Liberty Tax Service® by 1-800-790-3863 (Press option 2 followed by option 5) to request that their personal information is not sold or otherwise exchanged with third parties. Customer service representatives would be available from Monday to Friday, 9AM to 5PM EDT/EST.
The effective date of this notice is 10/01/2019.
California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018
In accordance with the California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018; you have the right to request from Liberty Tax Service®:
The categories of your personal information that are collected;
The categories of sources from which your personal information is collected. During the previous 12-month period Liberty Tax® has generally collected a consumer’s name, address, social security number, phone number, email address and dependent’s name, address, social security number, phone number, email address;
The business or commercial purpose for the collection or sale of your personal information;
The categories of third parties with whom personal information is shared;
That your personal information be deleted; and
The specific pieces of personal information which have been collected.
If your personal information is sold or disclosed for a business purpose by Liberty Tax Service®, you have the right to learn:
That categories of your personal information that have been collected;
The categories of your personal information that have been sold and the categories of third parties to whom your personal information has been sold; and
The categories of your personal information that have been disclosed to a third party. During the previous 12-month period, upon prior consumer permission, Liberty Tax Service® has disclosed to third parties a consumer’s name, address, social security number, email address and dependent’s name and email address.
You may exercise the above rights by either calling by 1-800-790-3863 (Press option 2 followed by option 5), customer service representatives would be available from Monday to Friday, 9AM to 5PM EDT/EST. Or through the following link https://www.libertytax.com/online/ccpa-request
Subpage
